ARSLAN RAZI

Mississauga, ON L5M 8C8, Canada | Email: arslan.razi@outlook.com | Phone: 647 860 2211

PROFILE SUMMARY

Outstanding **Product Management Professional** with over 10 years of experience in multiple industries. Strong analytical thinking and problem-solving skills with extensive experience leading complex enterprise **software development** projects. Excellent communication skills and interpersonal skills, great in building **lasting relationships** with clients. Exceptional **organization** skills, with proven experience in research and documentation of business and solution requirements. Advocate for professional development through continuous learning. **Certified Business Analyst** from the University of Toronto. **Software Product Management (SPM®) Certificate** from **Silicon Valley** based Product School.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- With expertise in collecting and analyzing data to drive meaningful insights, developed a comprehensive **bid management** system for a large **construction company** and reduced time spent on opportunity management and reporting by **50%**
- Led the development of a high-quality software product called SignatureMaster™ written in Java, and
 JavaScript, with MySQL database. For the past 7 years, I have ensured that our System Architecture
 is robust and secure. To date, our customers from different sectors like construction, insurance,
 engineering firms, and government have trusted us with over 683,000 documents for e-Signatures
 and e-Seals

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Software Development Life Cycle (Agile Scrum / Waterfall)
- Business Requirements Document (BRD), System Requirements Specification (SRS)
- Data Modeling, Process Modeling & UML (use cases, scenarios, activity, sequence diagrams)
- User Stories, Acceptance Criteria, Test Strategy, Test Plans, Backlog Grooming, & Sprint Planning
- Java, JavaScript, microservices, RESTful APIs, AWS, SQL and NoSQL databases, GIT, Node.js, HTML
- Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Camtasia Studio, Snagit, Visio, draw.io, JIRA, Confluence
- Presentations and Walkthroughs, Product Strategy, QA, Digital Market Strategy
- Investigate & resolve Technical Issues, Data Management, Excellent Customer Support
- Analytical Skill, Wireframes, Mockups, Engineering, Design, Cloud, User Interface, UX/UI, CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Xenex Enterprises Inc. Toronto, ON
Software Engineering - Software as a Service

Jul 2015 - Present www.xenex.ca

Senior Product Manager,

Aug 2018 - Present

- Successfully delivered real-time billing system handling over CA\$1.5 million annually
- Established and maintained product roadmap, Influenced overall product vision

Senior Business Analyst,

Jul 2015 - Jul 2018

- Served as the key conduit to business stakeholders for solution requirements and conducted analysis for all phases of the formal systems development life cycle for various projects
- Successfully implemented Agile Scrum methodology and conducted regular training sessions
- Translated project objectives and high-level requirements into use cases and specifications
- Gathered and documented business, functional and non-functional requirements
- Performed systems analysis and requirements management, acted as a subject matter expert for clarification of business requirements and objectives for development and test teams
- Ensured customer satisfaction and acted as primary contact for key external clients
- Planned and facilitated requirements workshops, to discover key requirements and recommended solutions to save time and development cost
- Trained new resources on domain knowledge, best practices for development, and quality assurance
- Worked **cross-functionally** to guide products from conception to launch

Business Analyst, HUSYD INC. Mississauga, ON *Software Solutions*

Nov 2013 - Jun 2015

www.husyd.com

- Developed and managed Project Charters, Work Breakdown Structures, Risk Management Plans,
 Communication Plans, Resource requirements, Cost Estimates, Schedules, and supporting details
- Acted as a Scrum Master and successfully implemented agile scrum methodology for multiple teams
- Led requirements gathering sessions to identify and resolve **business systems issues**, documented, and maintained business and systems requirements, delivered presentations to key stakeholders
- Provided technical support, and created various reports, plans, risk management, and audit deliverables for reporting to senior management
- Collaborated with clients to incorporate their needs and requirements, and worked with Engineering, UX/UI, Marketing, Sales, and External Partners to define and build great experiences
- Developed technical documentation and coordinated releases with other departments

Project Manager, Standard Communications *Warid Telecom - Sales and Customer Service*

Apr 2005 - Jul 2013

www.waridtel.com

- Consistently identified and assessed new opportunities through customer feedback, competitor analysis, and internal team consultation
- Thoroughly researched industry best practices and documented financial, business, billing, sales, and distribution processes to achieve sales volumes of US\$5.5 Million / year
- Reduced IT infrastructure maintenance cost by 50 %, created **technology roadmap** and Implemented accounting software, business applications, cloud file sharing, and backup system

Page: 2 of 3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

Business Account Manager, Standard Carpets

Aug 1999 - Mar 2005

Manufacturers and Exporters of Hand-Knotted Carpets & Rugs

www.standard-carpets.com

- Achieved around 60% growth in revenues consistently for 5 years by developing and maintaining business relationships with international clients, leadership in product design and development
- Successfully increased business volume by adding 22 new international clients and represented my organization at international trade fairs and exhibitions
- Ensured compliance with export quality standards and timely delivery of orders by effectively managing resources and production scheduling
- Effectively worked with vendors to design, **build**, and **implement** inventory control business application and **integrated** solutions

EDUCATION

Software Product Management (SPM®) Certificate

Product School - Toronto May 2018

Credential Identifier ID 11547055

Certificate in Business Analysis Aug 2015

University of Toronto

Bachelor's Degree (Four Years) Apr 2012

World Education Services - Canadian Equivalency

Master of Business Administration (MBA) - Finance & Banking Aug 1999

Lahore School of Economics

Page: 3 of 3